<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video | Random thoughts | Hari KT]]></title>
  <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/categories/video/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harikt.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-12T21:12:00+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://harikt.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hari K T]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Routing in PHP With Aura.Router]]></title>
    <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/2014/04/26/web-routing-in-php-with-aura-dot-router/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-26T20:30:10+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://harikt.com/blog/2014/04/26/web-routing-in-php-with-aura-dot-router</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It took sometime for me to create a series of screencast on
<a href="http://auraphp.com">aura</a>. So my plan to start a series of
screencasts starts with <a href="https://github.com/auraphp/Aura.Router">Aura.Router</a>
version 2.</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/hBV_BKP1WIY "></iframe></div></p>

<p>Yes, I have made some mistakes, but I do love to hear your feedback
and interest for the future screencast.</p>

<p>The next one will be on <a href="https://github.com/auraphp/Aura.Dispatcher">Dispatcher</a>
If you want to cover something special in the
<a href="https://github.com/auraphp/Aura.Dispatcher">Dispatcher</a> I will try to
address it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Selenium a Good Tool for Testers to Record the Action]]></title>
    <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/2009/08/26/selenium-good-tool-testers-record-action/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-26T21:20:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://harikt.com/blog/2009/08/26/selenium-good-tool-testers-record-action</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3527/3858966507_9aef76db9d.jpg" alt="image" />Learning Zend framework made me explore many new tools . The selenium IDE which is an add on for Mozilla is a wonderful tool for testers . For eg : we are humans and we may forget the actions done what all things we do . But we can record our clicks and inputs using selenium IDE . So when an error occurs we can show the developer what happens and what was the input entered etc .  I am really excited to see the Selenium IDE . I hope you testers and developers too will love this wonderful addon . Currently Selenium is supported by the browsers given below .  I have taken the list from the site . So if you are interested please do visit the site and get more information .  Browser Selenium IDE Selenium Remote Control Selenium Core Firefox 3 Record and playback tests Start browser, run tests Run tests Firefox 2 Record and playback tests Start browser, run tests Run tests IE 8b1 not supported ? ? IE 7 not supported Start browser, run tests Run tests Safari 3 not supported Start browser, run tests Run tests Safari 2 not supported Start browser, run tests Run tests Opera 9 not supported Start browser, run tests Run tests Opera 8 not supported Start browser, run tests Run tests Others not supported Partial support possible* Run tests**</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
