<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Book | Random thoughts | Hari KT]]></title>
  <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/categories/book/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harikt.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-13T19:34:35+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://harikt.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hari K T]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Give Away: Getting Started With Laravel 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/2014/01/24/give-away-getting-started-with-laravel-4/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-24T20:51:46+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://harikt.com/blog/2014/01/24/give-away-getting-started-with-laravel-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the help of Packt Publishing, there is a small contest started for
Giveaway of the book, <a href="http://bit.ly/KwzF9j">Getting Started with Laravel 4</a>.</p>

<p>And three lucky winners stand a chance to win a digital copy of
<a href="http://bit.ly/KwzF9j">the book on Laravel 4</a>.
Keep reading to find out how you can be one of the Lucky Winners.</p>

<p>Overview:</p>

<p>Provides a concise introduction to all the concepts needed to get started with Laravel</p>

<p>Walks through the different steps involved in creating a complete Laravel application</p>

<p>Gives an overview of Laravel&rsquo;s advanced features that can be used when
applications grow in complexity.</p>

<p>Learn how to build structured, more maintainable, and more secure applications
with less code by using Laravel</p>

<h2>How to Enter?</h2>

<p>All  you  need  to  do  is  head  on  over  to  the  <a href="http://bit.ly/KwzF9j">Book  Page</a>,<br/>
look  through the product description of the book and drop a line via the  comments below
this post to let us know what interests you the most about this book.
Then tweet the same using the book link: <a href="http://bit.ly/KwzF9j.">http://bit.ly/KwzF9j.</a>  It’s that simple.</p>

<p>Winners will get an e­copy of the Book.</p>

<h2>Deadline</h2>

<p>The contest will close on 9th Feb 2014. Winners will be contacted by email, so be sure
to use your real email address when you comment!</p>

<p>Happy PhPing!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book on Aura Moved to Manual]]></title>
    <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/2013/09/07/book-on-aura-moved-to-manual/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-07T12:08:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://harikt.com/blog/2013/09/07/book-on-aura-moved-to-manual</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some days back I wrote about a WIP of
<a href="http://harikt.com/blog/2013/07/09/the-book-on-aura/">The Book on Aura</a></p>

<p>It got some attention and pull requests.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/koriym/the-book-on-aura-ja">Akihito Koriyama</a>
have already started to convert the documentation to Japanese.</p>

<p>And today I am happy to announce that it is officially going to the
manuals.</p>

<h2>Contributing</h2>

<p>Fork
<a href="https://github.com/auraphp/auraphp.github.com">https://github.com/auraphp/auraphp.github.com</a>
and contribute to the manuals.</p>

<p>The manuals are in different languages. Currently<br/>
<a href="https://github.com/koriym/the-book-on-aura-ja">Akihito Koriyama</a>
is working on Japanese translation.</p>

<p>We are aware some parts of the manual needs a rewrite / more explanation.
If you are interested to learn and contribute get in touch via
<a href="http://groups.google.com/group/auraphp">http://groups.google.com/group/auraphp</a>.</p>

<p>If you are looking for library documentation check
<a href="http://auraphp.com/packages/">packages documentation</a>.
The manuals is to show you how to use Aura Framework, which is built
on top of the <a href="http://auraphp.com/packages/">aura libraries</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chance to Win Free Copies of Packt’s New Book on Zend Framework 2.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/2013/08/23/chance-to-win-free-copies-of-packts-new-book-on-zend-framework-2-dot-0/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-23T11:59:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://harikt.com/blog/2013/08/23/chance-to-win-free-copies-of-packts-new-book-on-zend-framework-2-dot-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have teamed up with <a href="http://www.packtpub.com">Packt Publishing</a> to organize a contest
of its newly published book on
<a href="http://www.packtpub.com/zend-framework-2-0-by-example-beginners-guide/book">Zend Framework 2.0 by example</a></p>

<p>And 3 lucky winners stand a chance to win eBook copies of the book.
Keep reading to find out how you can be one of the Lucky Winners.</p>

<h2>Overview of the book</h2>

<ul>
<li><p> Master application development with Zend Framework 2.0</p></li>
<li><p> Learn about Zend Framework components and use them for functions such as searching, image
processing, and payment gateway integrations</p></li>
<li><p> Integrate third-party services for media sharing and payment processing</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>How to Enter ?</h2>

<p>All you need to do is head on over to the
<a href="http://www.packtpub.com/zend-framework-2-0-by-example-beginners-guide/book">book page</a>
and look through the product description of the book and drop a line via the
comments below this post to let us know what interests you the most about this book.
It’s that simple.</p>

<p>Deadline:The contest will close in 1 weeks time (ie 30th August 2013).
Winners will be contacted by email, so be sure to use your real email
address when you comment! Hurry up as you could be one of the few lucky
ones to get yourself a free ebook of the latest released title.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[REST API Design Rulebook by Mark Massé; O'Reilly Media]]></title>
    <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/2012/07/17/rest-api-design-rulebook-by-mark-masse/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-17T23:35:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://harikt.com/blog/2012/07/17/rest-api-design-rulebook-by-mark-masse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everyone has been hearing the buzz REST. As web services and api for websites are becoming popular, all are busy developing REST api&rsquo;s for their websites. What exactly is REST? REpresentational State Transfer (REST) is a style of software architecture for distributed systems such as the World Wide Web. REST has emerged over the past few years as a predominant Web service design model. This is what wiki mentions . The book REST API Design Rulebook by Mark Massé; O'Reilly Media will teach you some rules which needs to be followed. This book has really helped me to understand some of the basic concepts of HTTP protocol. Yes really I was able to understand more on REST and how it should be represented etc. Probably you would have noticed websites with format .html , .json , .xml . If you have ever thought its REST, then its not :&ndash;) . Do you know a trailing forward slash (/) should not be included in URIs ? Underscores (_) should not be used in URIs ? There are more rules , but you can read and learn the rest from the book. The book has a total of 94 pages, but will serve you for a good reference. It also introduces WRML (<a href="http://www.wrml.org/">http://www.wrml.org/</a>) . Cons : Yes I feel there are some cons for the book. There are some examples when introducing WRML like the one below . {syntaxhighlighter class=&ldquo;html&rdquo;} application/wrml; format=&ldquo;<a href="http://api.formats.wrml.org/application/json">http://api.formats.wrml.org/application/json</a>&rdquo;; schema=&ldquo;<a href="http://api.schemas.wrml.org/soccer/Player">http://api.schemas.wrml.org/soccer/Player</a>&rdquo; {/syntaxhighlighter} But when you point your browser to <a href="http://api.formats.wrml.org/application/json">http://api.formats.wrml.org/application/json</a> you will get a 404. Example url : Its always a good way to mention example.com than mentioning <a href="http://api.schemas.wrml.org/soccer/Player">http://api.schemas.wrml.org/soccer/Player</a> . There are at many places its happening . You will not get completely on a first read when the chapters are moving, but sometimes you may want to read it many times. But I loved this book for I learned some basic stuffs really and also this is always a reference for future. In a rating of 5 , I will rate 4 . If you are interested in this book, you can buy this from REST API Design Rulebook by Mark Massé : <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920021575.do">http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920021575.do</a> Pages: 116 Print ISBN:978-1-4493-1050-9 | ISBN 10:1-4493-1050-8</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With OAuth 2.0 by Ryan Boyd; O'Reilly Media]]></title>
    <link href="http://harikt.com/blog/2012/04/26/getting-started-with-oauth2-by-ryan-boyd/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-26T22:46:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://harikt.com/blog/2012/04/26/getting-started-with-oauth2-by-ryan-boyd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OAuth the future of login? People are bored of registering and remebering user passwords on different websites. So the future of OAuth or using it in your daily life when developing website or apps is not that much far. Already many websites have been using it. This book <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920021810.do">Getting Started with OAuth 2.0</a> by Ryan Boyd published by O'Reilly Media is an awesome must read book. The author Ryan is a developer advocate at Google focused on enabling developers to extend Google Apps and build businesses on top of Google technology. He previously worked on OpenSocial and led the developer relations team for Google’s AtomPub APIs. Ryan has a great of knowledge of what he is talking about. The concepts of oauth was easy to understand, he has provided enough examples on how to use it in PHP, Javascript and HTML. I have already written an article at phpmaster<a href="http://phpmaster.com/integrating-with-facebook/">integrating facebook with php</a>. So if you ever thought of integrating oauth 2.0, its good to learn the concepts, so you can just relay on Http client library. Its a small 65 page book, but is worth . The book doesn&rsquo;t include or teach you how you can create your own oauth server , that is ok for its getting started with oauth. This book deserves a Rating of : 10 / 10 . Anything more you need to know? Title:Getting Started with OAuth 2.0 By: Ryan Boyd Publisher:O'Reilly Media Formats: Print Ebook Safari Books Online Print: February 2012 Ebook: February 2012 Print ISBN:978-1-4493-1160-5 | ISBN 10:1-4493-1160-1Ebook ISBN:978-1-4493-1159-9 | ISBN 10:1-4493-1159-8 Website : <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920021810.do">http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920021810.do</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
